James Allan Hall

Data Scientist

JAllanHall@gmail.com | 317-501-6460 | linkedin.com/in/j-allan-hall | San Francisco, CA 94109

SUMMARY

Skilled data scientist with experience ranging from early stage startups to large enterprises with thousands of employees. I am currently designing custom insight dashboards at **Cerebra Tech**. While I have management experience, I prefer serving as an individual contributor helping tech companies come up with creative solutions to complex problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- PROGRAMMING / FRAMEWORKS: SQL, AWS, Spark, Airflow, HDFS, Docker, BigQuery, Python, Presto, Hadoop
- PACKAGES: NumPy, Pandas, SparkNLP, PostgreSQL, Tensorflow, PyTorch, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, Google Analytics
- DATA SCIENCE: Bayesian Neural Nets, Recommendation Engines, NLP, Clustering, Computer Vision, Forecasting
- DATA VISUALIZATION: Tableau, Bokeh, Domo, Segment, D3, Sisense (Periscope), Mode, Plotly, Data Studio, Looker

EXPERIENCE

CEREBRA TECH | Data Scientist [Full-Time Contract]

Trend analysis for companies with >\$100M in subscription revenue

San Francisco, CA

May 2020 - Present

- Analyze unstructured text data, build NLP and topic clustering pipelines for segmentation and recommendation engine.
- Build social media listening dashboards for subscription based retailers including MADISON-REED.
- Automate analysis from structured & unstructured sources into actionable recommendations for key stakeholders.

PROFOUND WORK | Data Scientist

Incubator and Consulting Group

San Francisco, CA 2016 - 2020

- Designed data visualizations for HARVARD UNIVERSITY using Tableau, D3.js and ArcGIS to present research shared phenotypes; the goal is to uncover evolved adaptations with potential relevance to human health challenges.
- Developed computer vision pipeline for INTERACTIVE PROJECTION to enhance real-time tracking for custom interactive systems - see featured projects.
- Contracted with production projects including NLP of customer reviews, sentiment analysis, multi-touch attribution, affinity and propensity models, A/B testing, cohort analysis, experiment design, streaming pipelines, data mining, ETL.
- Built intuitive Infographics and automated dashboards in Tableau to communicate insights and strategic recommendations for cross-functional, non-technical, and C-level stakeholders given ambiguous, open-ended goals.

WARP | Co-Founder

San Francisco, CA 2016 - 2018

Top-rated iOS app leveraging AI technology to swap out backgrounds and create stickers

- Designed original wireframes and computer vision architecture for startup; designed experiments with AI applications, object recognition, A/B testing design and flow. Result: brought product to market in 3 months preview the app.
- Communicated data insights intuitively, built insight automated dashboard aggregating customer analytics from internal and external sources. Result: grew to top-rated mobile app for photography in-app store.

Stop-loss provider - assumes the risk of catastrophic claims exceeding healthcare fund threshold

2009 - 2017

- Developed anomaly detection model on unbalanced datasets to mitigate fraud, anti-money laundering, and suspicious claims. Result: Increased underwriting efficiency by 17%.
- Optimized pricing and underwriting techniques for large datasets using SQL, Python-based Machine Learning for risk forecasting, Excel and Tableau to visualize. Result: improved underwriting profit by 10%.
- Identified a gap in the market, managed cross-functional stakeholders to develop and bring to market 3 new international products. Result: extended our reach down market and created cross-selling opportunities.
- Identified opportunities to drive growth in market reach through optimized acquisition campaigns, uncovered underserved markets for Lloyd's coverholder. **Result:** 3x premiums from \$8.4M to \$25M.

Spun coverholder company out of Lloyd's, and negotiated acquisition with Xchange Benefits in 2017.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

INDIANA UNIVERSITY

B.S., Double Major: Chemistry and Music

Activities: Men's Crew; piano in jazz and funk bands, won the battle of the bands, released 2 albums, toured the US

WHARTON SCHOOL - UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA - Business Analytics Certificate

INTERESTS

- Part-time lecturer at UC Berkeley currently teaching a fintech bootcamp to undergrads and grad students at Berkeley
- Guardsmen Campership Chair organize events to help raise \$2M+ annually for at-risk youth
- Farm from a Box Advisor on agtech startup featured in NYT, FastCompany
- Spent 1.5 years after college traveling the world, worked in orphanages / taught English in Kenya, India, Thailand
- Other Interests: skiing, sailing, cooking via sous-vide, playing with my Australian Shepherd "Indy"